Subtitle Provide by dramacool.asia Translator [Admin.@YNG]
Untertitel bereitgestellt von dramacool.asia Translator [Admin.@YNG]
=The Maid=
=The Maid=
=Episode 18=
=Episode 18=
Shen Yuqing.
Shen Yuqing.
The one who wants you dead
The one who wants you dead
is your biological father.
is your biological father.
I don't have a father.
I don't have a father.
His Highness favors you more than me.
His Highness favors you more than me.
If you'd just admitted being Shen Yuqing earlier,
If you'd just admitted being Shen Yuqing earlier,
with Father's opportunistic nature,
with Father's opportunistic nature,
he might have wavered between us.
he might have wavered between us.
But you stubbornly refused to reclaim your identity.
But you stubbornly refused to reclaim your identity.
You dug your own grave.
You dug your own grave.
Shen Yuanjin.
Shen Yuanjin.
How does it feel to lose your mother?
How does it feel to lose your mother?
For the rest of your life,
For the rest of your life,
you'll never sleep peacefully again.
you'll never sleep peacefully again.
Lin Jifu and Madam Su
Lin Jifu and Madam Su
will haunt you forever.
will haunt you forever.
The Duke has arrived.
The Duke has arrived.
The Ministers of War, Revenue, and Justice have arrived!
The Ministers of War, Revenue, and Justice have arrived!
- Xiao.
- Xiao.
Xiao.
Xiao.
Outrageous!
Outrageous!
Who gave you the audacity
Who gave you the audacity
to threaten the Prince Regent with troops?
to threaten the Prince Regent with troops?
Xiao,
Xiao,
are you alright?
are you alright?
we didn't mean to offend His Highness.
we didn't mean to offend His Highness.
The troops
The troops
are absolutely furious.
are absolutely furious.
Indeed.
In der Tat.
Your Highness, please calm down.
Your Highness, please calm down.
The Western Army's Six Loyalists
The Western Army's Six Loyalists
have always cherished soldiers.
have always cherished soldiers.
When they learned
When they learned
I was in danger,
I was in danger,
in their urgency,
in their urgency,
they inevitably overstepped boundaries.
they inevitably overstepped boundaries.
Xiao.
Xiao.
The demoness attempted to assassinate the Duke.
The demoness attempted to assassinate the Duke.
By law, she should be executed.
By law, she should be executed.
The demoness caused a mutiny,
The demoness caused a mutiny,
threatening the nation's foundation.
threatening the nation's foundation.
She deserves death.
She deserves death.
Your Highness,
Eure Hoheit,
be the Empress Dowager's order,
be the Empress Dowager's order,
we came to oversee.
we came to oversee.
Once it's time,
Once it's time,
the fire must be lit.
the fire must be lit.
Fifth Sworn Brother guards the border.
Fifth Sworn Brother guards the border.
He's always hated evil.
He's always hated evil.
If he hears of this,
If he hears of this,
he'll surely bring the Western Army
he'll surely bring the Western Army
straight to the capital.
straight to the capital.
By then,
By then,
no one could stop him.
niemand konnte ihn aufhalten.
With all of you present today,
With all of you present today,
I'd like to see for myself
I'd like to see for myself
who among you dares to rebel.
who among you dares to rebel.
My lady,
My lady,
the Duke and senior officials have all arrived.
the Duke and senior officials have all arrived.
Don't waste this opportunity.
Don't waste this opportunity.
Don't worry.
Mach dir keine Sorge.
I've been waiting
I've been waiting
for this moment for three years.
for this moment for three years.
You're not watching the secondary consort.
You're not watching the secondary consort.
Where are you going?
Where are you going?
How does the discussion proceed in the main hall?
How does the discussion proceed in the main hall?
No matter what happens,
No matter what happens,
when the time comes,
when the time comes,
the fire must be lit.
the fire must be lit.
I fear the Prince Regent's retaliation.
I fear the Prince Regent's retaliation.
Better confirm first.
Better confirm first.
Lady Zheng,
Lady Zheng,
you're indeed the traitor.
you're indeed the traitor.
Fortunately, my father anticipated this.
Fortunately, my father anticipated this.
You shameless fool.
You shameless fool.
Let me go!
Let me go!
(No! Can't let Shen Yuanjin take Lady Zheng.)
(No! Can't let Shen Yuanjin take Lady Zheng.)
Move!
Bewegen!
My lord,
My lord,
the rope's chafing my shoulders.
the rope's chafing my shoulders.
Could you adjust it slightly?
Could you adjust it slightly?
I'm the Prince Regent's secondary consort.
I'm the Prince Regent's secondary consort.
His Highness still favors me.
His Highness still favors me.
When he emerges,
When he emerges,
I'll have him kill you
I'll have him kill you
to join me in death!
to join me in death!
You won't escape anyway.
You won't escape anyway.
Fire!
Feuer!
She dares take such a risk?
She dares take such a risk?
Hurry! Drag them away!
Hurry! Drag them away!
Xiyan!
Xiyan!
Save Lady Zheng!
Save Lady Zheng!
Go save her.
Go save her.
Understood.
Understood.
Ye Xiyan,
Ye Xiyan,
you got a death wish?
you got a death wish?
You're anxious?
You're anxious?
Zip it.
Zip it.
Among those you must protect,
Among those you must protect,
have I now joined their number?
have I now joined their number?
The demoness prophecy
The demoness prophecy
and the assassination attempt
and the assassination attempt
were all schemes devised by the Duke
were all schemes devised by the Duke
to frame Consort Ye.
to frame Consort Ye.
Preposterous!
Absurd!
Guards!
Wachen!
Drag her out and beat her to death.
Zerrt sie raus und prügelt sie tot.
My lord,
Mein Herr,
the Minister of Justice hasn't spoken.
der Justizminister hat sich nicht geäußert.
Must your reach extend
Muss sich Ihre Reichweite erweitern
beyond your jurisdiction?
außerhalb Ihrer Zuständigkeit?
The assassins were the Duke's men.
Die Attentäter waren Männer des Herzogs.
To survive, Nanxing and I
Um zu überleben, Nanxing und ich
had no choice but serve him.
hatte keine andere Wahl, als ihm zu dienen.
I've been wronged, yet I can't get justice.
Mir wurde Unrecht getan, aber ich kann keine Gerechtigkeit erlangen.
Your Highness,
Eure Hoheit,
honorable generals and lords, please see through the truth.
Ehrenwerte Generäle und Lords, bitte durchschauen Sie die Wahrheit.
Gentlemen,
Herren,
you shared life-and-death bonds
Sie teilten Bande auf Leben und Tod
with my husband.
mit meinem Mann.
Does his death
Ist sein Tod
not strike you as suspicious?
Kommt Ihnen das nicht verdächtig vor?
The Duke's lust
Die Lust des Herzogs
drove him to assault me.
trieb ihn dazu, mich anzugreifen.
When my husband discovered this,
Als mein Mann das entdeckte,
the Duke murdered him with his own hands.
der Herzog ermordete ihn mit seinen eigenen Händen.
Afterward,
Später,
he blamed enemy spies,
er beschuldigte feindliche Spione,
and then used mourning rites as pretext
und dann Trauerriten als Vorwand benutzt
to defile me
mich zu beschmutzen
before my husband's coffin.
vor dem Sarg meines Mannes.
Lady Zheng!
Dame Zheng!
You're the wanton one
Du bist der mutwillige
who seduced me.
der mich verführt hat.
You schemed to enter
Du hast geplant, einzudringen
the Duke's Mansion.
das Herrenhaus des Herzogs.
You're lying!
Du lügst!
Would I abandon being a general's wife
Würde ich es aufgeben, die Frau eines Generals zu sein?
to become a wronged ghost
ein geschädigter Geist werden
in your household?
in Ihrem Haushalt?
Xiao.
Xiao.
My lord,
Mein Herr,
do you recall this dagger?
Erinnern Sie sich an diesen Dolch?
Back then,
Damals,
you used it
du hast es benutzt
to kill my husband.
meinen Mann zu töten.
To this day,
Bis heute
his blood stains remain.
seine Blutflecken bleiben.
This Fishgut Sword
Dieses Fischdarmschwert
was bestowed upon you by my father.
wurde dir von meinem Vater verliehen.
Yet you defile it with vile deeds.
Und doch beschmutzt ihr es mit abscheulichen Taten.
All these years,
All diese Jahre,
I'm not the only one who have suffered
Ich bin nicht der einzige, der gelitten hat
under the Duke's tyranny.
unter der Tyrannei des Herzogs.
Gentlemen,
Herren,
you've been fighting abroad.
Sie haben im Ausland gekämpft.
How could you know the torment your households endured?
Wie konnten Sie wissen, welche Qualen Ihre Haushalte erdulden mussten?
Your concubine Wu,
Deine Konkubine Wu,
your daughter Baozhen,
deine Tochter Baozhen,
and your cousin...
und dein Cousin ...
They all fell victim
Sie alle fielen zum Opfer
to this wolf in noble's clothing!
zu diesem Wolf im Adelspelz!
Xiao!
Xiao!
Very well, Xiao!
Sehr gut, Xiao!
Madwoman.
Verrückte.
I should've silenced you sooner.
Ich hätte dich früher zum Schweigen bringen sollen.
Do you think
Meinen Sie
I don't want to die?
Ich will nicht sterben?
Long have I yearned for death.
Lange habe ich mich nach dem Tod gesehnt.
But I don't dare,
Aber ich traue mich nicht,
and I can't.
und ich kann nicht.
If I die,
Wenn ich sterbe,
none would clear
keiner würde klären
my husband's name.
der Name meines Mannes.
My death
Mein Tod
would free you
würde dich befreien
to greater villainy.
zu größerer Schurkerei.
Your Highness,
Eure Hoheit,
these records contain
diese Aufzeichnungen enthalten
years of evidence
Jahre der Beweise
against the Duke.
gegen den Herzog.
Payroll fraud,
Lohnbetrug,
false military claims,
falsche militärische Behauptungen,
and embezzle funds.
und Gelder veruntreuen.
Examine the Western Army's ledgers
Untersuchen Sie die Hauptbücher der Westarmee
for full proof.
für den vollständigen Beweis.
(Evidence of the Duke's crime)
(Beweise für das Verbrechen des Herzogs)
Gentlemen,
Herren,
you've been deceived all these years.
Sie wurden all die Jahre getäuscht.
I beg Your Highness
Ich bitte Eure Hoheit
and everyone here
und alle hier
to deliver justice
für Gerechtigkeit sorgen
for those women,
für diese Frauen,
my husband,
mein Ehemann,
and the Western Army.
und die Westarmee.
Hong!
Hong!
Don't heed her ravings.
Schenken Sie ihrem Geschwätz keine Beachtung.
Help me silence her.
Helfen Sie mir, sie zum Schweigen zu bringen.
The Western Army's Six Loyalists
Die sechs Loyalisten der Westarmee
were sworn to live and die together.
schworen, gemeinsam zu leben und zu sterben.
Yet for your own selfish desires,
Doch für deine eigenen egoistischen Wünsche,
you murdered Sixth Sworn Brother,
du hast den Sechsten Schwurbruder ermordet,
raped his wife,
seine Frau vergewaltigt,
and violated our families.
und unsere Familien verletzt.
How dare you
Wie kannst du es wagen
claim to be our sworn brother?
Behaupten, unser geschworener Bruder zu sein?
You beast!
Du Biest!
The Duke conspired against an imperial general.
Der Herzog hatte sich gegen einen kaiserlichen General verschworen.
Send him to the death cell.
Schicken Sie ihn in die Todeszelle.
The chaste widow Lady Zheng
Die keusche Witwe Lady Zheng
bore disgrace to seek justice.
erduldete Schande, um Gerechtigkeit zu suchen.
She is innocent.
Sie ist unschuldig.
Dear Ministers, any objections?
Sehr geehrte Minister, gibt es Einwände?
- You administer justice impartially.
- Sie üben unparteiisch Recht.
- We accept the verdict wholeheartedly.
- Wir akzeptieren das Urteil voll und ganz.
General of the West,
General des Westens,
Mi Hong, heed your orders!
Mi Hong, befolge deine Befehle!
Yes!
Ja!
The Western Army needs immediate leadership.
Die westliche Armee braucht sofortige Führung.
You shall temporarily
Sie werden vorübergehend
assume full command
die volle Kontrolle übernehmen
of the Western Army.
der Westarmee.
As your command!
Wie Ihr Befehl!
Thanks for your fair judgment.
Danke für Ihr faires Urteil.
Send the Duke
Schick den Herzog
to the imperial prison.
ins kaiserliche Gefängnis.
- Understood!
- Verstanden!
Hong!
Hong!
You can't do this!
Das kannst du nicht machen!
Hong, please!
Hong, bitte!
He seeks to weaken the Western Army!
Er versucht, die westliche Armee zu schwächen!
Hong!
Hong!
Don't fall for his schemes!
Fallen Sie nicht auf seine Machenschaften herein!
He deserves this.
Er hat das verdient.
Karma has finally come.
Endlich ist Karma gekommen.
That monster!
Dieses Monster!
Finally apprehended!
Endlich gefasst!
Worse than swine!
Schlimmer als Schweine!
Beat him to death!
Schlag ihn tot!
Kill him!
Töte ihn!
I am the Duke!
Ich bin der Herzog!
Dare any of you strike me?
Wagt es einer von euch, mich zu schlagen?
Who dares?
Wer wagt es?
Monster!
Monster!
Hit him!
Schlag ihn!
You brat!
Du Göre!
Hong.
Hong.
Sixth Sworn Brother can't rest in peace.
Der sechste geschworene Bruder kann nicht in Frieden ruhen.
This verdict
Dieses Urteil
shall bring peace to him,
wird ihm Frieden bringen,
his wife,
seine Frau,
and our families
und unsere Familien
who have suffered.
die gelitten haben.
Save me.
Rette mich.
Father,
Vater,
don't you recognize me now?
erkennst du mich jetzt nicht?
You...
Du...
You're...
Du bist...
♪I once fell into deep love♪
„Ich habe mich einmal tief verliebt“
♪Caught in a drama of love and hate♪
„Gefangen in einem Drama aus Liebe und Hass“
♪Trapped in self-made cages♪
???Gefangen in selbstgebauten Käfigen???
♪To whom should I direct my questions♪
„An wen kann ich meine Fragen richten?“
♪Heal my wounds from past dreams♪
???Heile meine Wunden aus vergangenen Träumen???
♪Fate bestowed me both joy and pain♪
„Das Schicksal hat mir sowohl Freude als auch Schmerz beschert.“
♪Left me a kiss of love and hate♪
???Hat mir einen Kuss der Liebe und des Hasses hinterlassen???
♪Who will unravel my dreams so deep♪
???Wer wird meine so tiefen Träume enträtseln???
♪Who will save me from this lonely place♪
„Wer wird mich aus diesem einsamen Ort retten?“
♪Who will give me back my lonely grace♪
???Wer gibt mir meine einsame Gnade zurück???
♪I dare not ask the infatuated ones♪
„Ich traue mich nicht, die Verliebten zu fragen“
♪As the moonlight thickens♪
„Wenn das Mondlicht dichter wird“
♪What I await♪
???Worauf ich warte???
♪Which heartless soul♪
???Welche herzlose Seele???
♪Love departs, hatred persists♪
„Die Liebe vergeht, der Hass bleibt bestehen“
♪I woke too soon to bygone bonds♪
„Ich bin zu früh aufgewacht und habe die Bindungen vergangener Zeiten verloren.“
♪Forgetting the lost one in old dreams♪
???Den Verlorenen in alten Träumen vergessen???
♪No longer waiting for estranged souls♪
„Nicht länger auf entfremdete Seelen warten“
♪Memories flow in the deep night♪
„Erinnerungen fließen in der tiefen Nacht“
♪Illuminating lonely spirits♪
???Einsame Seelen erleuchten???
♪Become an ordinary mortal♪
„Werde ein gewöhnlicher Sterblicher“
♪Next spring will open heart's doors♪
„Im nächsten Frühling öffnen sich die Türen des Herzens“
♪Not seeking a specific beloved♪
???Suchen Sie keinen bestimmten Geliebten???
♪Gracefully embracing affections♪
„Zärtlichkeiten anmutig annehmen“